Love never dies.
Bram Stoker's Dracula is a romance, horror film
directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
Centuries-old vampire Count Dracula travels to Victorian London, where he becomes obsessed with Mina Murray—the
fiancée of his solicitor, Jonathan Harker—believing her to be the reincarnation of his long-lost love.
Dracula, played by Gary Oldman.
Mina Murray / Elisabeta, played by Winona Ryder.
Professor Abraham Van Helsing, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Jonathan Harker, played by Keanu Reeves.
Lucy Westenra, played by Sadie Frost.
Lord Arthur Holmwood, played by Cary Elwes.
Bram Stoker's Dracula is a 1992 American Gothic horror film produced and
directed by Francis Ford Coppola and written by James V.
Hart, based on the eponymous 1897 novel Dracula by Bram Stoker.
The film features an ensemble cast led by Gary Oldman, Winona Ryder, Anthony Hopkins,
Keanu Reeves, and introducing Sadie Frost in her film debut as Lucy Westenra.
Set in 19th-century England and Romania, it follows Count Dracula (Oldman), a vampire who falls in
love with Mina Murray (Ryder), the fiancée of his solicitor Jonathan Harker (Reeves).
When Dracula begins terrorizing Mina's friends, Professor Abraham Van Helsing (Hopkins), an
expert in vampirism, is summoned to bring an end to his reign of terror.
Its closing credits theme "Love Song for a Vampire" was
written and performed by Annie Lennox.
Bram Stoker's Dracula was theatrically released in the United
States on November 13, 1992 by Columbia Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for Coppola's direction, the production values,
and Oldman's performance, although Reeves' performance was very heavily criticized.
The film opened at the top of the box office, grossing $215.9 million against its $40 million budget, and was nominated in four categories at the 65th Academy
Awards, winning Best Costume Design for Eiko Ishioka, Best Sound Editing, and Best Makeup, while also being nominated for Best Art Direction.
The film explores themes of adultery, london,
england, transylvania, vampire, bite.
The tone is dark and emotional.